Abraham: Now that you have conducted
your personal skills analysis and
assessed the skills you have against
various roles in cyber security it is
time to create a personal development
plan, to help you decide what you
need to do in order to achieve your
goal of working in cyber security.
Nicole: To do this you should
use SMART goals or targets.
So, what exactly are these?
SMART is an acronym which stands for
Abraham: Specific, Measurable,
Achievable, Relevant, Timebound.
Nicole: Specific means each goal or
target should be clear and focussed
on what you want to accomplish.
Think about why it is important,
who is involved, where will it
happen what resources are needed!
For example:
Abraham: ‘I want to be able to
gain the experience and skills
to become a team leader in cyber
security within my organisation’
Nicole: Measurable is a way of tracking
your progress and keeping motivated.
It should ask questions like ‘how
will I know that I am on track to
do this?’ And ‘what will I need
to do to help make it happen?’ Try
setting a timeline for your progress.
Abraham: Achievable means that the
goals and targets you set are realistic.
By breaking down your goals into smaller
steps can make them easier to achieve.
Don’t forget we all have to
walk before we try to run!
Think about how long some of the
skills you need may take to get
and remember set goals that you can
control and are not down to others.
Nicole: Relevant is about making
sure that you goal means something
to you, and it really matters, is
worthwhile and achievable at this time.
Abraham: Time-bound is all about
setting target dates giving you
something to focus on and work towards.
These should be realistic and are best
broken down into smaller goals and
remember don’t be too specific, if
something is worth doing it’s worth
doing well and shouldn’t be rushed.
Nicole: And finally, it’s always
worthwhile factoring in contingencies
as we are all well aware of what
can happen when we least expect it!